Liang Song

E-mail sonilaicc@gmail.com

Phone 316-516-6876

Address 1605 E Cedar PI, Olathe, KS 66062

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/liang-song-05b1ba14a/

Summary

I'm a recent college graduate with 1 year of experience in Java and Python programming language. I'm a passionate, energetic software programmer that possesses skills in coding, math, and logic analyzing. I'm seeking an entry level, full-time position in software engineering to leverage skills in software application development, collaboration, communication and leadership.

Technologies

Java

Intermediate knowledge of object-oriented programming

Python

Intermediate knowledge, clean organization

JavaScript

Intermediate knowledge with an amateur experience in front-page design

NodeJS

Entry level, knowledge of simple web server connection

MongoDB

Entry level, knowledge of senior design experience

Experience

2016-08 - 2017-01

College Student Software Developer

Wichita State University Senior Design Group

- Created a **service data tracker system** on vehicle using Android device with Java and JavaScript. Built and maintained an Android application, web server and user database with Ionic 2, MongoDB and NodeJS.
- NodeJS was used to be our server which communicated between Android application and MongoDB with basic functions such as user login and user registration.
- Developed queries and tables for MongoDB.
- Generated scientific data and reports to aid key directorate's decision.

2016-01 - 2016-07

Software Analysis

Wichita State University Senior Design Group

- Created a *vehicle ignition mandatory interrupt system* device which would connect to the vehicle and allow or disallow the vehicle to start.
- Developed an Android based mobile application as the user input with the Raspberry PI 3 running on Linux to control the electronics through a GPIO(General-Purpose Input/Output) board.
- Wrote in Python to setup Raspberry PI 3 functions such as data input, output, Bluetooth connection and audio.
- Wrote JavaScript functions for frontend application.

Education

2013-08 - 2017-07

Wichita State University (WSU), Wichita, KS

- B.S. in Computer Science
- Minor in Math